

CONTACT

Clegg Street Wapping London E1W 3NL



07985 742983



andy.little@hotmail.co.uk



www.andylittleweb.com

SKILLS

React

Javascript

Python

Django

CSS / SCSS

SQL

Git Hub

Jest

React-testing-library

Pytest

Flask

Figma

ANDY LITTLE

Full-Stack Developer

ABOUT ME

I have loved computers from a young age. At 9 I spent my school breaks building computer games with a friend. At 13 I taught myself HTML and some basic C programming. I was also very passionate about music; I earned a degree from ACM and pursued this as a career. I created an original jazz funk band comprised of some of the countries best jazz musicians and together we played some of London's most prestigious jazz clubs. I was lucky enough to become a member of Redtenbacher's Funkestra - a band I have admired since a teenager. I also taught, played in function bands for corporate events and worked for a music software startup called Knowledge Rocks.

Along the way I picked up some basic graphic design skills in Adobe. I find this very enjoyable as it has a lot in common with music: balance, space, contrast, direction of attention, symmetry and motif.

Other useful skills I learnt from the music industry are how/when to lead a team and how/when to support and serve a team. The industry taught me tenacity, self-motivation, resourcefulness and grit. I learnt to work well under stress and to be reliable and dependable.

For the last 2+ years I have been studying computer science and working as a web developer.

EDUCATION

Harvard's CS50

"A robust understanding of computer science with an emphasis on problem solving." I learnt about algorithms, data structures and databases. The primary language was C and problem sets included building an encryption program, spell checker, image filters and a web app for buying and selling stocks.

CS50 Web Programming with Python and Javascript

Topics covered were database design, scalability, security, writing/using APIs, testing, UX/UI, Bootstrap, React and leveraging cloud services like GitHub and Heroku. Problem sets included recreating simplified versions of Wikipedia, Ebay and Facebook.

Self Study

Since these courses I have continued my learning everyday. I have taken courses on Javascript and React and I continue to delve deeper into programming/keep up-to-date with the latest changes. I have been building and deploying websites, problem solving and being self-reliant. I have interned at two companies and worked for six months as a full time developer.



EDUCATION

CS50x

Harvard University 2020 12 week online course

CS50 WEB

Harvard University 2020 12 week online course

BA HONS Music Practice ACM 2013-16 (2:1)

ANDY LITTLE

www.andylittleweb.com

EXPERIENCE

LeavingCard.com

June 2021 - December 2021

I worked for 6 months at www.leavingcard.com. I built a Python package which pulled sales info from the company database and cleaned/analysed the results. We profiled our target customers and analysed the efficiency of advertising campaigns. I also created a React app for displaying the data to the team using graphs, charts, tables and timelines. The website was intended to be shared with investors at a later stage so style and presentation were also important.

While at leaving card I received a lot of mentorship. Key points I learnt about where test driven development and object oriented design, in particular:

- separation of concerns model vs controller
- composition vs inheritance
- dependency inversion and polymorphism
- software architecture
- maintaining docs
- managing environments inline with 12 factor app

Wise Works

April 2021 - June 2021

I gained 2 months work experience/mentorship at www.wiseworks.ai. Their site was a complex one that was built by contractors sometime ago. I helped to get the site running locally. This was an enormous challenge for me as the site was written with Vue and Node with Typescript, which are not in my skill set. Over two months I worked hard to get an overview of Node, Vue, MongoDB and Docker. I learnt about web hooks, Ngrok and database replica sets as well as touching on Learna and Tailwind and makefiles.

Accomplish

February 2021 - March 2021

I interned at www.accomplish.world. I helped them automate their benchmarking model, Helix. "In a consulting capacity, Andy combined his technical know-how with broader strategic vision to help us see what a digital future would like for our business." - Adam Grainger, co-founder.

To view my personal projects and client work please visit

www.andylittleweb.com